<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Mark Bennett</title><description>Software developer, music lover, and 2015 Venture for America Fellow. </description><link>http://mwbennett.github.io/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 01:29:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mwbennett.github.io/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Blogging at Hack Reactor</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HR W1D4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've officially arrived in the trenches at &lt;a href="http://www.hackreactor.com/"&gt;Hack Reactor&lt;/a&gt;! My first few days here have been a complete blur, in the best possible way. Despite my having impossibly high expectations coming into the program, thus far Hack Reactor has completely lived up to the hype. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hack Reactor strongly encourages students to maintain a blog during their time here, a suggestion that I have decided to follow despite my mild hatred for writing. Ultimately, I expect the value of blogging will outweigh the &lt;em&gt;certain&lt;/em&gt; discomfort I will experience by publicly publishing written words on a regular basis. (If you're struggling to understand why this is such a big deal, it may be helpful to know that I typed, deleted, and retyped various versions of this sentence six times before ultimately moving on. TL;DR: writing is hard.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="whyblog"&gt;Why blog?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know a few people who really love the saying "writing is thinking." As I already mentioned, I'm not wild about writing, and I'd hate to think that necessarily indicates an aversion to thinking too. So I'm inclined to believe that  we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; able to think without writing, whereas it's nearly impossible to write clearly without thinking. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, my reasoning for blogging is pretty simple - I see it as a way to force myself to engage with my own thoughts and understanding. Should they ever get read by others, I expect these entries will also help correct misunderstandings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="posttopics"&gt;Post topics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows what I'll actually end up writing about, but here are some angles through which I expect to approach posts over the next 13 weeks: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirm understanding of technical concepts.&lt;/strong&gt; I'll attempt to share interesting details or intricacies of a particular language or framework as I learn them. I doubt the content of these particular posts will be highly novel, but maybe that's the &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@aliciatweet/overcoming-impostor-syndrome-bdae04e46ec5"&gt;impostor syndrome&lt;/a&gt; talking. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convey my Hack Reactor experience.&lt;/strong&gt; At this point, there are &lt;a href="http://kevinhamiltonsmith.com/hack-reactor-student-blogs/"&gt;tons of blogs&lt;/a&gt; that document the experiences of Hack Reactor students (and &lt;a href="http://blog.thejsj.com/"&gt;many&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.austentalbot.com/"&gt;many&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://tylermcginnis.com/category/hack-reactor/"&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; more since that post was published). I skimmed over more than a few of these before applying to the program, and the quality of the blogs was one of the many indications that Hack Reactor was the real deal. I feel it's only fair that I attempt to follow in the footsteps of providing useful insights for future Hack Reactor applicants and students. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share resources and solutions for potentially unique problems.&lt;/strong&gt; It's likely that ~95% of my time over the next 13 weeks will be spent trying to solve broken code. I expect that on occasion, my code might be broken in a somewhat interesting way. When this happens, I figure it's a good excuse for a post&lt;html&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/html&gt;both to share a solution to a problem others might experience, and to ensure I fully understand the solution that I've implemented (back to the old "writing is thinking" argument). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Articulate non-technical growth.&lt;/strong&gt; Hack Reactor will help me become an exponentially better software engineer than I am now. It will also, I hope, help me grow in ways that aren't explicitly related to my technical abilities. I hope to occasionally reflect on that development as well. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="bloggingscheduleandconventions"&gt;Blogging schedule and conventions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Before I go on, please know that I firmly believe nobody else in the world cares about my blogging schedule. That said, making a written commitment to post consistently will help create the illusion of external expectations, which might be enough to trick me into sticking with it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial goal is to blog three times per week. Each week, I'll aim to cover one technical topic, one topic that relates to Hack Reactor (directly or indirectly), and one wild card topic. (Yes, these categories aren't at all mutually exclusive...I'm setting expectations without actually committing to anything!) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout my time at Hack Reactor, I'll be prefixing all my posts with "HR W#D#" to indicate how far into the program I am when writing. Today, for example, is Hack Reactor week 1, day 4&lt;html&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/html&gt;or HR W1D4&lt;html&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/html&gt;as seen at the top of this post. For reference, the course runs six days a week, for thirteen weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll close with my first endorsement of an awesome tool. All my posts will include a comments section thanks to &lt;a href="https://disqus.com/"&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;. Should anyone happen to stumble across a post, please feel free to comment. You can do so without an account, but you should probably just sign up. &lt;a href="https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/1109643-new-profiles-f-a-q-"&gt;Disqus profiles&lt;/a&gt; are pretty great. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://mwbennett.github.io/2015/03/26/blogging-at-hack-reactor/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">44e4d641-f6ee-4abd-af32-0caa0eb1adf6</guid><category>Hack Reactor</category><category>Blogging</category><dc:creator>Mark Bennett</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 06:51:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hello World</title><description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Mark Bennett, and I am an aspiring software developer and entrepreneur. I'm preparing to begin a new adventure in two parts: in two months I start at &lt;a href="http://www.hackreactor.com/"&gt;Hack Reactor&lt;/a&gt;, a three month intensive program to become a more capable coder and developer; immediately afterward, I will be joining &lt;a href="http://www.ventureforamerica.com/"&gt;Venture for America&lt;/a&gt; as a 2015 Fellow. I'm supremely exciting for what's to come. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to use this blog as a way to track my progress and share some of the things I learn and think about along the way. It will also provide a great excuse to more routinely focus on being thoughtful and introspective. With any luck, perhaps these posts &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; at some point become of mild interest to people other than myself... but for now, I won't hold my breath. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://mwbennett.github.io/2015/01/26/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">b32b3471-eb90-4e59-8a4b-dd2896352749</guid><category>Personal</category><dc:creator>Mark Bennett</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 07:26:08 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>